bellaonline.com 2001-06-04

# Bella Online Privacy Policy

 You Are Here:  HOME > PRIVACY POLICY

 P R I V A C Y   P O L I C Y 

This statement discloses the privacy practices for BellaOnline.com ("Website"). Because this Website wants to demonstrate its commitment to respecting your privacy and to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet, it has agreed to disclose its information practices. You can expect to be notified of: 

  1. What personally identifiable information is collected
  2. How the information is used
  3. With whom the information will be shared
  4. This Website's opt-out policy
  5. This Website's policy on correcting and updating personally identifiable information
  6. This Website's policy on deleting or deactivating your name from our database

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to Bella-Online.com by sending an email to [info@bellaonline.com](mailto:info@bellaonline.com) and writing "Privacy Policy" in the subject line.

Bella-Online is currently seeking review and certification of its Privacy Policy by an independent privacy organization. The terms of this Privacy Policy are subject to revision in order to obtain certification.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of our Terms of Use Agreement. Pursuant to the Terms of Use, this Privacy Policy is subject to modification at any time. You are responsible to review the Privacy Policy before using the site or providing any information.

How We Collect Information 

This Website collects information that falls into one of two categories -- personally identifiable information and aggregated information. Personally identifiable information is information that can be used to identify you. Aggregated information is information that is not associated with a specific user, such as the number of people who visit the Website from various states.

We collect personally identifiable information whenever you voluntarily submit it to the Website. Examples of this type information include when you answer our polls, enter sweepstakes or contests, fill out the registration page, send us feedback or post in our chat rooms or message boards. You always have the option of choosing not to reveal this personally identifiable information to us, although certain services may be unavailable if you do not. In the event of a complaint, we may also receive and collect personally identifiable information about you from other parties in our Website or from other users or third parties who may communicate information to us about you in relation to that complaint.

In addition, we collect and store statistics and other information about the online activities of our visitors on an aggregated (collective) basis. For example, we track the number of people who view each page, the order in which pages are viewed, and other information to learn which features are the most popular and to refine our design and marketing efforts.

Information We Gather or Track 

Information on general usage and any optional personal details you provide to us will be used to provide you with enhanced features such as customized content, access to our Chat Rooms and message boards, and the ability to participate in any of our BellaOnline communities. The following are details of the information we collect: 

  * BellaOnline, Inc. collects data so that we may display personalized content to our visitors. Additionally, usage information may be analyzed so that we can judge our system's performance or execute your customized features. 
  * Your computer reaches us via a particular IP, ( **I** nternet **P** rotocol), address. This can tell us things like what part of the world you're connecting from. Or what service provider you are using. 
  * Your browser offers so-called "cookies" which -- if you allow their use -- store small amounts of data on your computer about your visit to any of our sites. Cookies assist us in tracking which of our features you like best. And when you re-visit our site, cookies can enable us to customize our content according to your preferences. However, cookies tell us nothing about you personally unless you specifically give us additional information. 
  * Our registration form asks for contact and demographic information used to send news about our products or promotional material from our partners. You will be able to opt-out of receiving any mailings. Demographic information may be used to customize the display of our site to you by showing content that we think might be of interest or related to your past visits.
  * Surveys may ask for contact information or unique identifying information to increase the value of the results. Contests may require contact information or other demographic/personal information in order to determine your eligibility.
  * Some of the banner ads displayed in our site are provided by outside companies. These ads may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Web site, cookies received with banner ads are collected by our advertisers and we do not have access to this information. Cookies in and of themselves do not contain any personally identifiable information about you.

How We Use and Disclose Your Information

Both aggregated and personally identifiable information is used to operate and enhance our site and enhance your on-site experience by displaying content and marketing messages that we believe will be of interest to you.

Except as described below or otherwise indicated, we do not sell your personally identifiable information to third parties. On some pages where we ask for your personally identifiable information, we may tell you that the data we are collecting on that page will be shared with third parties. Information gathered from such pages may be shared with or sold to third-parties.

We produce aggregate reports for advertisers. For example, we tell advertisers how many people saw or clicked on an ad and additionally, how many people saw or clicked on ads in different portions of our service. Where available, we may offer additional information about viewer characteristics. _However this does **not** include personally identifiable information about you or your online usage patterns._ Our advertisers allow us to provide our service to you. In return, they need to know how to effectively place their ads to potential customers. 

We'll use your email contact information to provide you with newsletters to which you subscribe, or for similar information we think you may find of interest. However, you can choose to opt out of these mailings. By providing your contact information you will be eligible to acquire user ID's and passwords that will allow you to participate in our community features, including chat and bulletin boards. 

We also share or sell your personally identifiable information with third parties who provide services to our Website or are affiliated with our Website in order to enhance the functionality available to you as part of the Website, and to provide you with new products and services such as email and Member services. 

Some online activities necessarily lead to disclosure of your personally identifiable information to third parties, such as when you include your name and email address in a postcard or when you order merchandise in the Store. For such activities, a separate warning may not be provided. Your choice to disclose personally identifiable information in these cases is voluntary.

In addition, you agree that Bella-Online.com may assign, sell, license, or otherwise transfer to a third party, your name, address, e-mail address, member name and any other personal information in connection with an assignment, sale, joint venture, or other transfer or disposition of a portion or all of the assets or stock of Bella-Online.com or its affiliated entities.

Who Can Use Collected Information and How

  * As mentioned above, we provide our advertisers with aggregate reports on advertising activity. 
  * Feedback is used both by BellaOnline, Inc. staff as well as the individual Hosts for each of the BellaOnline Hosted sites. Hosts not only link to content from their sites and provide their own original content, but would have available to them any information that you send them directly. Hosts use of this information is bound by the principles and practices expressed here.
  * Please be aware that if you voluntarily disclose information online, personal or otherwise, that information can be collected and used by others. For example, using chat, bulletin boards, or your e-mail, if you post personal information online you may receive unsolicited messages from others. BellaOnline, Inc. will have no means to control this. 

Controlling or Changing Your Information

You can access and update your personal information, including changing your subscriptions to our email newsletters, by going to the [members.bellaonline.com](http://members.bellaonline.com/) and following the instructions on that page. There you can review, modify, or delete the personally identifiable information we maintain about you. You can also opt in or out of receiving commercial communications from us or having your information shared with or sold to third parties. While you can modify or delete the information that we maintain, we cannot modify or delete the information that has already been provided to a third party. In addition, some personally identifiable information is required by the Terms of Use to maintain your Membership on BellaOnline.com. If you delete that information, you may lose access to the Website.

Cookies and Other Tracking Methods

We use cookies (see [cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/) for complete information) or IP addresses for a number of uses, including allowing you to store your password without having to constantly re-enter it, helping us to tailor a Web site or a marketing message to better match your needs and interests, and allowing us to better understand how users use our site. You are always free to instruct your web browser to decline our cookies if it has the capability to do so, but some parts of our site may not work properly if you do.

Other Sites

If you provide any information on your own or directly to parties who provide service to the Website (such as WhoWhere?), any merchants in our Store or any other sites you encounter on the Internet (even if these sites are branded with our branding), Bella-Online Website privacy policies to not apply to the use or disclosure of the personal information you disclose to them. On our website we use Delphi Forums to provide message boards and chat rooms. Delphi collects information through these services and uses that information in accordance with its own privacy and security policies. For more information about Delphi’s policies please see [delphi.com](http://www.delphi.com/).

Limits on Our Abilities

We cannot fully ensure that your private communications and other personally identifiable information will not be disclosed to third parties. We may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. If we need to investigate or resolve possible problems or inquiries, we can (and you authorize us to do so) disclose any information about you to private entities, law enforcement or other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate. 

Security

We use industry-standard efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal identifiable information, such as firewalls and Secure Socket Layers where appropriate. However, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet.

We hope this policy clarifies our procedures regarding your personal information. We at BellaOnline.com encourage you to learn as much as you can about your privacy on the Internet. To learn more, visit TRUSTe at: <http://www.truste.org/> and GetNetWise at: <http://www.getnetwise.org/>.
